csoonline.com 2017-06-19

# Privacy Policies | CSO

online | print subscribers  | online registration

### Online Privacy Policy

This website ("Website") and associated websites are maintained by:

**CXO Media, Inc.  
492 Old Connecticut Path  
P.O. Box 9208  
Framingham, MA 01701-9208  
U.S.A**

The publisher of this Website ("Publisher") collects personally identifying information and data about individuals, their company, and their company's demographics (personally identifying information and data) including (i) when you provide information to us, such as when you register or sign up for any of our products such as publications, subscriptions, e-mails, contests, newsletters, memberships, RSS Feeds, webcasts, White Papers, online seminars, conferences and other communications with the Publisher, (ii) when you register or sign up on one of our Websites, or when you register for any other IDG Publishing Network products individually or through auto register, your information will be known to the Publisher and (iii) from time to time we may add other information that we collect from third party sources to enhance the information that you provided to the Publisher.

Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by the Publisher. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers. The Publisher reserves the right to change its privacy policy. However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifying information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our Website.

The Publisher or one of our IDG affiliated companies, or third party partners or advertisers may place online tracking technology such as a "cookie" in the browser files of a user's computer. The cookie itself does not contain any personally identifying information, except when such information has been supplied by a subscriber or registered user. In addition, cookies placed in the browser files of a user's computer by a third party advertiser, may be used by the advertiser to collect web viewing data to serve further online interest-based advertising, also known as online behavioral advertising.

If you have registered with our Website, the information in your cookie is used to provide a more personalized experience on our Website.

If you haven't registered with our Website, we may place a cookie on your system to help provide a more personalized experience. This cookie identifies you as a unique user by means of a tracking ID. However, if you have not registered on our Website, we cannot link that user ID with personally identifying information and data about you such as your name or e-mail address.

Other cookies without personally identifying information and data are used to enable the Publisher to manage the banner advertisements presented or personalized information to the user.

Browsers or third-party software can allow you to block the use of cookies while you surf our site. Or, you can use third-party "anonymizer" services to mask information in your cookies, or even general data such as your IP address. In such cases you would not be able to take advantage of most of the personalization services offered by the Publisher site(s).

The aggregated information we collect is used for a number of purposes including the following: 

  1. to improve the content and design of our Website
  2. to enable our audit bureau to verify our claims of traffic to our Website
  3. to help advertisers, potential advertisers or marketers assess the suitability of our Website for their ad campaigns
  4. as clear GIFs, also known as pixel tags, provided by our ad-serving company to help manage online advertising. These clear GIFS let our ad-serving company recognize a browser's cookie when a user visits our site. The information we collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable (It does not include your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address). For more information about our ad-serving company or for your choices about not having this anonymous information used, please visit [www.google.com/doubleclick](http://www.google.com/doubleclick/).
  5. The Publisher has contracted with DoubleClick to serve all advertising on our Website itself and through its e-mail newsletters and other products. When DoubleClick is serving ads, it recognizes certain types of non-personally identifiable information, such as a user's IP address, browser version or type, operating system, service provider and time zone. DoubleClick also uses cookies to note the general content of the sites that users visit over time in order to serve ads on this site and other sites. Any pages a user calls up on our Website aren't connected with personally identifiable information collected either on our Website or elsewhere. For more details about the non-personally identifiable information DoubleClick collects and the opportunity to opt out of such data collection, please visit [www.google.com/doubleclick](http://www.google.com/doubleclick/). We use web metric vendors to gather information to help us understand how users utilize our Website and other electronic products.
  6. We may create and use aggregate customer data to understand more about the interests of our customers and may use the data to offer goods and services we believe may be of interest to our customers, on behalf of the Publisher, its sister IDG companies, or select organizations.

Postal addresses, and other personally identifying information and data may be collected from our online users (and, as applicable, our print subscribers) and may be used to promote the Publisher's and other IDG companies' products and services, and may be rented and/or licensed to select outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the personally identifying information and data are rented and/or licensed for use and the users are required to target their offers carefully.

Telephone numbers may be collected from our online users (and, as applicable, our print subscribers) and may be used by the Publisher to collect re-qualification data, and may be used by the Publisher, IDG and other IDG companies, affiliates and its advertisers for promotional purposes. The Publisher may rent and/or license for use phone numbers to select outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the numbers are rented and/or licensed for use are required to target their offers carefully.

Mobile telephone numbers that are provided to the Publisher will be used to provide the products and services you've specifically requested, such as, but not limited to content delivery via sms text or other technologies, and for customer service related to the products and services you've requested. With your express consent, your mobile telephone number may be used to promote other products and services of the Publisher, as well as the products and services of other IDG companies. Further, your mobile phone number may, with your express consent, be used to promote the products and services of carefully chosen third parties. At any time you may "opt-out" of receiving communications via your mobile phone from the Publisher, other IDG companies, and third parties, by visiting [CSOOnline.com](http://www.csoonline.com/) or by clicking the unsubscribe link of any individual message you may receive. Because many phone companies recycle phone numbers, it is possible for users who purchase a new phone to receive messages that the previous owner had subscribed to or otherwise consented to receive.

Fax numbers may be collected from our online users (and, as applicable, our print subscribers) and may be used by the Publisher to collect re-qualification data, and may be used for surveys for the Publisher and third parties. Except as set forth in this policy no fax numbers are rented and/or licensed to outside firms.

E-mail addresses may be collected from our online users (and as applicable, our print subscribers), and may be used for re-qualification purposes. These e-mail addresses may also be used to collect feedback by members of our editorial or research team, to promote the Publisher's and IDG products and services, and they may be rented to select outside firms* and/or licensed for promotional purposes. When you provide your email address to us, you agree to receive email from outside firms, the Publisher and its sister IDG companies, and the IDG Network. With each e-mail use of the user's address you can individually opt-out of receiving further e-mail from outside firms, the Publisher, its sister IDG companies and the IDG Network. Offers for which the e-mail address is rented and/or licensed for use require the users to target their offers carefully.

(*If, however, you are a registered user and have indicated, either in response to a question asked during the registration process in place prior to the date this policy was last updated (see the date posted at the end of the policy), or otherwise, that you do not wish to allow your email address to be rented and/or licensed for use by outside firms, your email address will not be rented and/or licensed for use.)

Users who later decide they want to change any of their preferences may do so at [www.csoonline.com/newsletters/login](http://www.csoonline.com/newsletters/login) and <http://optouts.csoonline.com/index.html?dept_id=62>.

(Online users who are also print subscribers should refer to the print subscriber section of this policy which contains information on how to remove your name from our promotion list).

Our Website makes available a large library of content provided to us from third parties. In return for access to this content, we may ask you to provide us with personally identifying information. Once you have submitted your information, you will have access to the full library of third party content and will not be asked to provide that information again (unless you disable or otherwise modify your cookies). When accessing content contributed by a third party, your personally identifying information may be shared with those third parties, and the information will be governed by those parties' privacy policies as well as ours. The Publisher, nor its parent company, or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates, does not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of such third parties. If you do not wish to have your information shared with a third party, please do not access third party content on our site.

Our Website, or portions of our Website, may be sponsored by third party sponsors. Any personally identifying information you share on our Website when registering to receive access to any offer, including but not limited to premium access or newsletter content, may be shared with such sponsors for marketing purposes.

Our Website users should be aware that when they disclose personally identifying information (e.g., user name, address, company name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and E-mail address) in discussion forums, chat rooms or other areas that are publicly accessible by others, that information can be collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or parties. Neither the Publisher, nor its parent company or any of its subsidiaries or affiliates are responsible for any information that you provide in the above areas.

In the event that the ownership of this Website and/or any of the Publisher's other products and/or assets are sold or transferred, all lists and data which contain personally identifying information and data including for example user name, address, company name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and e-mail address, will be transferred to the new owner.

We may use or disclose personally identifying information if we have a good-faith belief that the disclosure is reasonably necessary (a) to satisfy applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request, (b) to enforce agreements we have with you, (c) to address fraud or security issues, or (d) to protect against harm to the rights, property, or safety of the Publisher, or our employees or customers.

back to top

### Print Subscriber and "Auto Register" Privacy Policy

The Publisher collects personally identifying information and data about individuals their company and the company's demographics (personally identifying information and data) (i) when you provide information to us, such as when you register or sign up for any of our products such as publications, subscriptions, RSS Feeds, web casts, White Papers, online seminars, conferences emails, contests, newsletters, memberships and other communications with the Publisher (ii) when you register or sign up on one or our websites or when you register for any other IDG Publishing Network products individually or through auto register, your information will be known to the Publisher and (iii) from time to time we may add other information that we collect from third party sources to enhance the information that you provided to the Publisher.

Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by the Publisher. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers. The Publisher reserves the right to change its privacy policy. However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifying information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our Website.

Subscribers and applicants for the Publisher's Print subscriptions are asked to complete a questionnaire with personally identifying information and demographics. The data is used in a number of ways including the following: 

  1. to improve the content of the Publisher's magazine(s) and other print product(s)
  2. to notify subscribers about re-qualification and renewal
  3. used by us for marketing the Publisher's products and services
  4. used by our audit bureau to verify cumulative demographic statistics
  5. used by the Publisher, IDG, its subsidiaries and its affiliates and IDC for research surveys
  6. used by Editorial for consultation with readers

Postal addresses, and other personally identifying information and data will be used to promote the Publisher's and IDG products and services, and may be rented and/or licensed to select outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the names are rented and/or licensed for use and the users are required to target their offers carefully.

Telephone numbers of the Publisher's print subscribers are used by the Publisher to collect re-qualification data and may be used by the Publisher, IDG, its subsidiaries and affiliates, and their advertisers for promotional purposes. The Publisher may rent and/or license for use telephone numbers to select outside firms for promotional purposes. Offers for which the telephone numbers are rented and/or licensed for use require users to target their offers carefully.

Mobile telephone numbers that are provided to the Publisher will be used to provide the products and services you've specifically requested, such as, but not limited to content delivery via sms text or other technologies, and for customer service related to the products and services you've requested. With your express consent, your mobile telephone number may be used to promote other products and services of the Publisher, as well as the products and services of other IDG companies. Further, your mobile phone number may, with your express consent, be used to promote the products and services of carefully chosen third parties. At any time you may "opt-out" of receiving communications via your mobile phone from the Publisher, other IDG companies, and third parties, by visiting [CSOOnline.com](http://www.csoonline.com/) or by clicking the unsubscribe link of any individual message you may receive. Because many phone companies recycle phone numbers, it is possible for users who purchase a new phone to receive messages that the previous owner had subscribed to or otherwise consented to receive.

Fax numbers of the Publisher's print subscribers are used by the Publisher to collect re-qualification data and may be used for surveys for the Publisher, IDG and its affiliates and third parties. Except as set forth in this policy, no fax numbers are rented and/or licensed to outside firms.

E-mail addresses of the Publisher's print subscribers are used for re-qualification purposes. These e-mail addresses may also be used to collect feedback from subscribers by members of our editorial or research team, to promote the Publisher's and IDG products and services, and they may be rented and/or licensed to select outside firms* for promotional purposes. When you provide your email address to us, you agree to receive email from outside firms, the Publisher, its sister IDG companies and the IDG Network. With each e-mail use of the user's address you can individually opt-out of receiving further email from outside firms, the Publisher and its sister IDG companies. Offers for which the e-mail address is rented and/or licensed for use require the users to target their offers carefully.

(*If, however, you are a registered user and have indicated, either in response to a question asked during the subscription/registration process in place prior to the date this policy was last updated (see the date posted at the end of the policy), or otherwise, that you do not wish to allow your email address to be rented and/or licensed for use by outside firms, your email address will not be rented and/or licensed for use.)

In the event that the ownership of the Publisher's print product or any of the Publisher's other products and/or assets are sold the all lists and data which contain personally identifying information and data including for example user name, address, company name, telephone number, demographic information, buying information, other data and e-mail address, will be transferred to the new owner.

We may use or disclose personally identifying information if we have a good-faith belief that the disclosure is reasonably necessary (a) to satisfy applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request, (b) to enforce agreements we have with you, (c) to address fraud or security issues, or (d) to protect against harm to the rights, property, or safety of the Publisher, or our employees or customers.

Print subscribers or applicants who do not want their names used in any of the above ways may write and ask to be removed from the promotion list. Requests should be sent to:

**IDG Enterprise  
Circulation Department  
PO Box 9208  
Framingham, MA 01701  
U.S.A.**

(Print subscribers who are also online users should refer to the online section of this policy which contains information on changing your online preferences).

back to top

### IDG Publishing Network Online Registration Privacy Policy

Below is the current policy regarding the usage of personally identifying information and data collected by the IDG Publishing Network. We reevaluate this policy on an ongoing basis based on feedback from readers. The IDG Publishing Network reserves the right to change its privacy policy. However, if there are any changes to the use of personally identifiable information and data that is different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on our website.

**About the IDG Publishing Network**

The International Data Group, Inc. (IDG) family of on-line and print publications consists of hundreds of award-winning titles including CIO, CSO, InfoWorld, Computerworld, Game Pro, Network World, Macworld and PC World. The IDG Publishing Network is a growing collection of IDG web sites that presently includes cio.com, csoonline.com, computerworld.com, infoworld.com, networkworld.com, macworld.com, pcworld.com and gamepro.com. A complete listing is available at [www.idg.com](http://www.idg.com/).

To access restricted content on any IDG Publishing Network web site you must be a member of the IDG Publishing Network. To become a member of the IDG Publishing Network, you need to provide certain information about yourself. Any of the IDG Publishing Network sites may use this identifying information for internal analytical and business development purposes and, to send you email. However, other forms of communication, including postal mail, may be directed to you pursuant to the site's specific privacy policy, as may be updated from time to time.

You can "opt-out" of receiving further email by clicking the appropriate links that appear at the bottom of any email you receive. If you do not want to receive other types of communication, including as applicable, postal mail, from the editor and publisher of the site, please refer to the site's privacy policy for the procedure to follow.

The IDG Publishing Network is intended for individuals over the age of 13 years old. Personal information may not be provided by anyone under 13 years of age. Further no one under 13 years old may participate in the forums or chat rooms or any other areas where public discussions may take place. In addition no one under that age of 18 may conduct any transactions for the purposes or purchasing or selling any items. Parents should be sure that their children are not conducting any of the above activities on the IDG Publishing Network.

If you have any questions or comments regarding the IDG Publishing Network or its use of information please send email to postmasterhelp@idgcommunications.com or write to us at:

**IDG Communications  
Customer Service, TSG Department  
492 Old Connecticut Path  
P.O. Box 9208  
Framingham, MA 01701-9208  
U.S.A.**

**Last updated:** May 13, 2015
